Puneet Soni

+91-7742114929 | puneetsoni.mail@gmail.com | puneetsoni.com | github.com/sonipuneet | linkedin.com/in/puneetsoni31

SUMMARY

I am a Software Engineer, with a deep interest in software and contemporary technology. I have track record of building and delivering full-stack applications through the entire process. Experienced in information gathering, development, testing and deployment.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering, JECRC University - Computer Science, August 2016

WORK EXPERIENCE

Accenture (December 2016 - Present)

Supply Chain Revenue Tool

• Responsible for the User Interface design and implementation for the Supply chain tool project for Royal Dutch Shell INC. (Based on calculating the revenue for the company products)

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, .NET, MySQL, MS-Excel.

Event Registration System

- Responsible for the design and implementation for the event registration system project. I was responsible for building the Admin and User portals, which helps to track, deleted and update all the orders that flow through the system
- Responsible for creating functional and automation test-suite for verification of an Event registration system and Accenture Job search portal.

Technologies: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Java, TestNG, Selenium, MySQL, MS-Excel.

Tribond Infosystems

(August 2016 - November 2016)

• Designed the UI/UX of Android and IOS application for messaging app using Photoshop. Also created a web UI for customer and admin portal in which user can login, add and update information.

Technologies: Photoshop, JavaScript, HTML, CSS.

Genx Softwares (April 2016 - July 2016)

Health care professionals

• Created frontend single page application using Bootstrap and Uikit for customers. Also created an admin console for doctors and users to add and update the information. Designed the backend using php.

Technologies: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MySQL, Bootstrap, Uikit and JQuery.

Pianta.com (Acquired by GO-JEK)

(January 2016 – March 2016)

Admin Console

 Designed and developed onboarding web console for service providers to provide their information and different services they want to offer. Console consists of services/events like create, edit, update and save.

Technologies: Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, MySQL, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Uikit and JQuery.

<u>Automated verification of Android and Web console</u>

 Responsible for creating automation test-suite for continuous verification of backend API and Android application.

Technologies: Java, TestNG and RestNG.

SELECTED PROJECTS

<u>DistJobScheduler - Asynchronous Workload Processing System</u>

(Major Project)

Designed and developed a distributed system that performs job admission, job scheduling and job execution.
 The system is divided into five main components: Job Client, Jobs API, Job Scheduler, Job Agent and Job Executor. Users can use Job Client to submit a job and query for its completion status via Jobs API. Once a job is submitted, Job Scheduler schedules the Job on the appropriate Job Agent to be executed via Job Executor.

Technologies Used: Java, Jersey, Gradle.

Online Banking System

(Minor Project)

• Designed an online Banking Portal using Java Server Pages (JSP). The portal consisted of services like Sign Up, Login and online money deposit, withdrawal and transfer.

Technologies Used: Java, MySQL, HTML, CSS.

TALKS/SEMINARS

• Apache Mesos - A Distributed Systems Kernel

• Apache Hadoop and MapReduce

• Smart Surveillance

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, C++, C, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, CSS, Bash

Software: Bootstrap, Foundation, jQuery, Uikit, MySQL, Windows, Linux (Ubuntu), Mac OS X

Tools: Dreamweaver CC, Atom, IntelliJ IDEA, Git